[
    {
        "category": "Advanced Programming",
        "question": "what language do u use",
        "options": [
            "pyhton",
            "python",
            "css",
            "C"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "python"
    },
    {
        "category": "database",
        "question": "sql is :",
        "options": [
            "a styling language",
            "a Structured Query Language",
            "a programming language"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a Structured Query Language"
    },
    {
        "category": "database",
        "question": "What is the purpose of the SQL SELECT statement?",
        "options": [
            "To insert data into a database",
            "To select data from a database",
            "To delete data from a database",
            "To update data in a database"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "To select data from a database"
    },
    {
        "category": "database",
        "question": "What is the purpose of the SQL WHERE clause?",
        "options": [
            "To specify the table from which to select data",
            "To filter records that meet a specified condition",
            "To join multiple tables together",
            "To sort records in ascending order"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "To filter records that meet a specified condition"
    },
    {
        "category": "database",
        "question": "What does the SQL LIKE operator do?",
        "options": [
            "Groups records based on a condition",
            "Returns the largest value in a column",
            "Searches for a specified pattern in a column"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Searches for a specified pattern in a column"
    },
    {
        "category": "database",
        "question": "Which aggregate functions are commonly used with the GROUP BY statement?",
        "options": [
            "COUNT() MAX() MIN() SUM() AVG()",
            "SELECT() INSERT() UPDATE() DELETE()",
            "JOIN() UNION() INTERSECT() EXCEPT()",
            "HAVING() WHERE() ORDER BY() DISTINCT()"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "COUNT() MAX() MIN() SUM() AVG()"
    },
    {
        "category": "Advanced Programming",
        "question": "What is the correct file extension for Python files?",
        "options": [
            ".pp",
            ".pt",
            ".py"
        ],
        "correct_answer": ".py"
    },
    {
        "category": "Advanced Programming",
        "question": "What is a correct syntax to exit the Python command line interface?",
        "options": [
            "exit()",
            "stop()",
            "end()"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "exit()"
    },
    {
        "category": "Advanced Programming",
        "question": "True or False: Indentation in Python is for readability only",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "category": "Advanced Programming",
        "question": "Which character is used to define a Python comment:",
        "options": [
            "'",
            "//",
            "#",
            "/*"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "#"
    },
    {
        "category": "Advanced Programming",
        "question": "What is a correct way to declare a Python variable?",
        "options": [
            "var x = 5",
            "#x = 5",
            "$x = 5",
            "x = 5"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "x = 5"
    },
    {
        "category": "Advanced Programming",
        "question": "Dictionary items cannot be removed after the dictionary has been created.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "category": "Advanced Programming",
        "question": "Which statement is a correct syntax to break out of a loop?",
        "options": [
            "end",
            "return",
            "break"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "break"
    },
    {
        "category": "Advanced Programming",
        "question": "What is the correct keyword for defining functions in Python?",
        "options": [
            "function",
            "func",
            "def"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "def"
    },
    {
        "category": "Advanced Programming",
        "question": "What is a function used for opening files?",
        "options": [
            "load()",
            "run()",
            "open()"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "open()"
    }
]